You can teach your dog to use a litter box.
There are many different solutions out there that have an attractant that will draw your dog to the litter in the box and are more acceptable for dog use than for cat use.
So look, go out and look for a dog litter box in particular.
They're also a little bit larger and have an easier entrance for them to make the dog more comfortable.
If your dog is already trained to pee pads or newspaper, you can start by putting pieces of those things in the box to draw the dog to go in the same location.
Dogs tend to like to use the same spot where they've gone before.
The same general area.
You can also bring in some of their feces from outside and put it in the litter box again to draw them to that and then just work slowly.
You might need to confine your dog until you think that they need to go to the bathroom and then only give them access to that litter box so that hopefully that's where they'll choose to go.
You might choose to use a dog litter box if you live in a high rise or an urban area where it's hard to get your dog outside to go to the bathroom.
Also, some dogs will not be comfortable going to the bathroom on concrete or gravel and so they might need an alternative to that.
There might also be a situation where you have a small dog and you're gone for a long period of time or you're going to be going away and somebody's only going to be coming to check on your dog once a day, which may not be recommended.
I would check with your landlord and make sure that these are all appropriate things for your building.
But, that might be another reason why you would choose to use a litter box for your dog.